Ready for the new **Google Consent Mode v2**? [Learn more »](https://www.consentmanager.net/google-consent-mode-v2/)✕

Data protection
===============

**Please note: This data protection declaration ONLY relates to the data processed by us when you visit or use our website. The data protection declaration does NOT describe the processing of data on third-party sites as part of our service as a consent provider. Please also note that we conclude an order processing contract (AVV) with ALL of our customers and that we EXCLUSIVELY carry out data processing as a contractor (“processor”). We do NOT process any data on our customers’ websites for our own purposes, but exclusively for and on behalf of our customers.**

overview
--------

#### Who are we?

We (“consentmanager”) are a Swedish-German company specializing in providing online services. We develop and distribute the “consentmanager” tool of the same name. This can be used to record and manage visitor consent to a website (colloquially “cookie banner”).

#### How do I reach consentmanager?

By post: consentmanager AB, Haltegelvägen 1b, 72348 Vasteras, Sweden

By email: mail@consentmanager.net

By phone: +46703823647 (no support!)

… or simply via our [contact form](https://www.consentmanager.net/contact/) .

#### What happens when I visit your site?

If you visit our website, we process data about you or your device. See [below](#Nutzung-unserer-Website) for details. If you agree, [we will also set cookies and evaluate the data](#Tracking) .

#### How about the cookies?

If you agree, we or the tools we use may set cookies on your device. [More details can be found here](#Tracking) .

#### What happens with my data?

We do not pass on your data to third parties without your consent. We also have agreements with all service providers to secure your data in the best possible way. [More about this here.](#Einbindung-von-Inhalten-Dritter)

#### What rights do I have?

You have various rights, such as the right to have your data correct, to have it deleted after processing, or to have it only processed or passed on with your consent. [You can find out more about rights here.](#Ihre-Rechte)

#### How can I protect my data?

We try to protect your data as best we can. In addition, you have the option to object to the processing at any time. [See here for more information.](#Ihre-Rechte)

General information about the processing of your data
-----------------------------------------------------

We (“consentmanager”) are legally obliged to inform you about the processing of your personal data (hereinafter “data”) when you use our website. We take the protection of your personal data very seriously. This data protection notice informs you about the details of the processing of your data and your legal rights in this regard. For terms such as “personal data” or “processing”, the legal definitions from Art. 4 DSGVO are decisive. We reserve the right to adapt the data protection declaration with effect for the future, in particular in the case of further development of the website, the use of new technologies or changes in the legal basis or the corresponding case law. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy from time to time and keep a printout or copy for your records.

scope
-----

The data protection declaration applies to all consentmanager pages, such as consentmanager.de, consentmanager.net, consentmanager.fr etc. It does not extend to any linked websites or internet presences from other providers.

Responsible
-----------

Responsible for the processing of personal data within the scope of this data protection declaration is:

consentmanager AB  
Haltegelvägen 1b  
72348 Vasteras  
Sweden

Phone: +46703823647 (no support!)

Email: mail@consentmanager.net

Questions about data protection
-------------------------------

If you have any questions about data protection with regard to our company or our website, you can contact our data protection officer:

Lawyer and data protection officer  
Peter Hense

Postal address:

Data Protection Officer  
c/o consentmanager AB  
Haltegelvägen 1b  
72348 Vasteras  
Sweden

Contact via the encrypted online form:

security
--------

We have taken comprehensive technical and organizational precautions to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, misuse, loss and other external disturbances. To this end, we regularly review our security measures and adapt them to the state of the art.

Your rights
-----------

You have the following rights with regard to your personal data, which you can assert against us:

* **Right to information:** You can request information in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR about your personal data that we process.
* **Right to correction** : If the information concerning you is not (or no longer) correct, you can request a correction in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR. If your data is incomplete, you can request a completion.
* **Right to erasure** : In accordance with Art. 17 GDPR, you can request the erasure of your personal data.
* **Right to restriction of processing:** In accordance with Art. 18 GDPR, you have the right to request that your personal data be restricted.
* **Right to object to processing:** You have the right, for reasons arising from your particular situation, to object at any time to the processing of your personal data, which is based on Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. e) or lit. f) GDPR takes place, according to Art. 21 para. 1 GDPR to object. In this case, we will not process your data further unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, and if the processing serves to assert and exercise or defend against legal claims ( Art. 21 Para. 1 GDPR). In addition, according to Art. 21 para. 2 GDPR, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes; this also applies to any profiling insofar as it is associated with such direct advertising. We draw your attention to the right of objection in this data protection declaration in connection with the respective processing.
* **Right to revoke your consent** : If you have given your consent to processing, you have the right under Art. 7 Para. 3 GDPR a right of withdrawal.
* **Right to data portability** : You have the right to receive the personal data that you have provided to us in a structured, common and machine-readable format (“data portability”) and the right to have this data transmitted to another person responsible if the Prerequisite of Art. 20 para. 1 lit. a, b GDPR (Art. 20 GDPR).

You can assert your rights by notifying the contact details given in the “Responsible” section or the data protection officer appointed by us.

If you believe that the processing of your personal data violates data protection law, you also have the right under Art. 77 GDPR to complain to a data protection supervisory authority of your choice. This also includes the data protection supervisory authority responsible for the person responsible:  
Data inspections, Integritetsskyddsmyndigheten, Box 8114, 104 20 Stockholm, Sweden, [imy@imy.se](mailto:imy@imy.se) .

use of our website
------------------

In principle, you can use our website for purely informational purposes without disclosing your identity. When accessing the individual pages of the website in this way, only access data is transmitted to our web space provider so that the website can be displayed to you. The following data is processed here:

* browser type/ browser version,
* operating system used,
* language and version of the browser software,
* date and time of access,
* host name of the accessing end device,
* IP address,
* Content of the request (specific website),
* access status/HTTP status code,
* websites accessed through the website,
* Referrer URL (the previously visited website),
* Notification of whether the call was successful
* amount of data transferred,
* Time zone difference to GMT.

The temporary processing of this data is necessary in order to technically enable the website visit and delivery of the website to your end device. The access data is not used to identify individual users and is not merged with other data sources. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests lie in ensuring the functionality of the website and the integrity and security of the website. The access data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required to achieve the purpose of their processing. In the case of the collection of data for the provision of the website, this is usually the case when you end your visit to the website.

**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

tracking
--------

In addition to the aforementioned access data, so-called cookies, pixels, browser fingerprinting or other tracking technologies are used when using the website. Cookies are small data packages with a sequence of numbers that are stored locally in the cache or hard drive of the browser used. Pixels are one-pixel images that are created opaque or in the background color of the website and are therefore not visible to the user. The pixel also collects information about your user behavior on the website. Fingerprinting technologies generate a unique fingerprint based on the browser settings and thus identify an individual browser. Using a script that every Internet browser runs automatically, information such as the resolution of the screen, fonts used, operating system, hardware information and integrated browser plugins can sometimes be collected, which in their specific combination can ultimately make it possible to trace back to a specific user . The tracking technologies serve to make our website user-friendly. The use of tracking technologies may be technically necessary or for other purposes (e.g. analysis/evaluation of website usage).

### Technically necessary elements

Some elements of our website require that the calling browser can be identified even after a page change. In the technically necessary elements, such as in particular cookies or similar methods of terminal device access, the following data is processed for the purpose of carrying out or facilitating electronic communication and providing an information society service requested by the user:

* Language settings,
* font settings,
* Log-in information (e.g. for our customer portals)
* Analysis of website usage (e.g. for the purpose of providing the necessary hardware resources)

The user data collected through technically necessary elements are not processed to create user profiles. We also use so-called “session cookies”, which store a session ID with which various requests from your browser can be assigned to the joint session. “Session cookies” are necessary for using the website. In particular, we can use it to recognize the end device used when you return to the website. We use this cookie to recognize you on subsequent visits to the website if you have an account with us; otherwise you will have to log in again each time you visit. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interest in processing consists in providing the special functionalities mentioned and thereby making the use of the website more attractive and effective. The “session cookies” are deleted as soon as you log out or, depending on which browser you are using and which browser settings you have made, when you close the browser.

**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

### Technically unnecessary tracking

We also use cookies, pixels, browser fingerprinting and other tracking technologies on the website to enable an analysis of the surfing behavior of users. For example, the following data is stored and processed:

* Frequency of page views
* Use of website functions (e.g. registration)

The legal basis for this processing is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. a) GDPR. The technically unnecessary cookies, pixels and other tracking technologies are automatically deleted after a specified period, which may differ depending on the tracking method. Insofar as we integrate third-party cookies or pixels and similar tracking technologies into our website, we will point this out to you separately below.

**You can revoke your consent to the processing of the respective provider at any time by calling up the consent tool via the icon at the bottom left of the website and unchecking the checkbox under “Advanced settings”. The lawfulness of the processing remains unaffected until the revocation is exercised.**

### Consent management platform consentmanager

We use our consent tool “consentmanager” to request consent for the processing of your end device information and personal data using cookies or other tracking technologies on our website. With the help of “consentmanager” you have the option of agreeing to or rejecting the processing of your end device information and personal data using cookies or other tracking technologies for the purposes listed in “consentmanager”. Such processing purposes can include the integration of external elements, integration of streaming content, statistical analysis, range measurement, individualized product recommendations and individualized advertising. You can use “consentmanager” to give or deny your consent for all processing purposes or to give or deny your consent for individual purposes or individual third parties. You can also change the settings you have made afterwards. The purpose of integrating “consentmanager” is to allow the users of our website to decide whether to set cookies and similar functionalities and to offer them the opportunity to change settings that have already been made as part of their continued use of our website. In the course of using “consentmanager”, we process personal data and information about the end devices used. Your data will also be sent to consentmanager (consentmanager AB, Håltegelvägen 1b, 72348 Västerås, Sweden). The information about the settings you have made will also be stored on your end device. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. c) GDPR in conjunction with Art. 7 para. 1 GDPR, insofar as the processing serves to fulfill the statutory obligations to provide evidence for the granting of consent. Incidentally, Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR the relevant legal basis. Our legitimate interests in processing lie in the storage of user settings and preferences in relation to the use of cookies and the evaluation of consent rates. Twelve months after making the user settings, you will be asked for consent again. The user settings made are then saved again for this period of time, unless you first delete the information about your user settings in the end device capacities provided for this purpose.

**You can object to the processing if the processing is based on Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

Contacting our company
----------------------

When contacting our company, e.g. B. by e-mail or via the contact form on the website, the personal data you provide (such as first and last name, telephone number or Skype name) will be processed by us in order to answer your request. In order to process inquiries via the contact form on the website, it is mandatory to provide a name and a valid e-mail address. At the time the message is sent to us, your IP address and the date and time of registration will also be processed. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR or Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR if contact is aimed at concluding a contract. If the request is aimed at concluding a contract, the details of your data are required and obligatory for the conclusion of a contract. If the data is not provided, it is not possible to conclude or implement a contract in the form of contacting us or processing the request. The processing of the personal data from the input mask serves solely to process the contact. If contact is made by email, this is also the necessary legitimate interest in the processing of the data. The other data processed during the sending process serve to prevent misuse of the contact form and to ensure the security of our information technology systems. In this context, the data is not passed on to third parties. We delete the data arising in this context after the processing is no longer necessary – usually two years after the end of the communication – or limit the processing if necessary to compliance with the existing statutory storage obligations.

**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

Processing for contractual purposes
-----------------------------------

We process your personal data if and to the extent that this is necessary for the initiation, justification, implementation and/or termination of a legal transaction with our company. The legal basis for this results from Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR. The provision of your data is necessary for the conclusion of the contract and you are contractually obliged to make your data available. If your data is not provided, it is not possible to conclude and/or execute a contract. After the purpose has been achieved (e.g. contract processing), the personal data will be blocked or deleted for further processing, unless we have given your consent (e.g. consent to the processing of the e-mail address for sending electronic advertising mail), a contractual Agreement, a legal authorization (e.g. authorization to send direct mail) or based on legitimate interests (e.g. storage to enforce claims) are authorized to further processing.

Your personal data will be passed on to third parties if

* it is necessary for the establishment, implementation or termination of legal transactions with our company (e.g. when passing on data to a payment service provider/a shipping company to process a contract with you), (Art. 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. b ) GDPR), or
* a subcontractor or vicarious agent, whom we use exclusively within the scope of providing the offers or services you require, requires this data (unless you have been expressly informed otherwise, such auxiliary persons are only entitled to process the data to the extent that this is necessary for the performance of the offer or service is necessary), or
* an enforceable official order (Art. 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. c) GDPR) exists, or
* there is an enforceable court order (Art. 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. c) GDPR), or
* we are obliged to do so by law (Art. 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. c) GDPR), or
* the processing is necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or another natural person (Art. 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. d) GDPR), or
* it is necessary for the performance of a task that is in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority (Article 6 (1) sentence 1 lit. e) GDPR), or
* we can invoke our overriding legitimate interests or a third party for disclosure (Article 6 (1) sentence 1 lit. f) GDPR).

Your personal data will not be passed on to other people, companies or bodies unless you have given your effective consent to such a transfer. The legal basis for processing is then Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. a) GDPR. Within the scope of this data protection information, we refer you to the respective recipients in relation to the respective processing operation.

customer account
----------------

In order to be able to use the services of consentmanager, you must create a customer account with the following information:

* First and Last Name,
* User name,
* Address,
* email address and
* self-selected password.

Furthermore, your IP address and the date and time of registration are processed at the time of registration. We use the double opt-in procedure for registration. After you have submitted the data required for registration, you will receive an email with an activation link. Only after the link has been activated by clicking will access to your customer account be created and registration successfully completed. In the case of later registrations (logins), the access data (user ID and password) you selected when you first registered must be entered. If the transmitted link is not confirmed within 24 hours, we will automatically delete it after one month at the latest. Otherwise, your data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required to achieve the purpose for which they were processed. This is the case for the data collected during the registration process when the registration on the website is canceled or modified.

The following functions are available to you in the login area:

* edit your profile data,
* view orders placed
* set up and edit the consent management platform for your own website.

If you use the login area of the website, e.g. B. to edit or view your profile data, we also process the personal data required to initiate or fulfill the contract, in particular address data and information on the method of payment. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR. The provision of your data is necessary and obligatory for the conclusion and implementation of the contract. If your data is not provided, you can neither register nor use the login area, ie it is not possible to conclude and/or execute a contract. Your data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required for the purpose of processing. This is the case after the customer account has been deleted, unless we are required by law to store the data. In this case we restrict the processing. Due to mandatory commercial and tax regulations, we are obliged to keep your address, payment and order data for a period of up to ten years.

Email Marketing
---------------

### Existing customer advertising

We reserve the right to use the e-mail address you provided when placing the order in accordance with the statutory provisions to send you the following content by e-mail during or after the conclusion of a contract, provided that you have not already objected to the processing of your e-mail address:

* technical information on the integration, setup and configuration of the consent management platform,
* new functions of the consent management platform, such as languages, designs, providers and the implementation of new requirements,
* new offers for services of our products and services,
* Invitations to company events.

The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR or Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR if the sending of electronic information for the execution of the contract (e.g. e-mails in an informational format) is required. If the processing is related to the execution of the contract, the details of your data are necessary and obligatory for the conclusion and execution of a contract. If your data is not provided, it is not possible to conclude or execute the contract by sending informational e-mails. In other cases, our legitimate interest in the processing mentioned lies in increasing and optimizing our services, sending direct mail and ensuring customer satisfaction. We delete your data when you end the usage process, but no later than three years after the end of the contract.

**We would like to point out that you can object to the receipt of direct mail and processing for the purpose of direct mail at any time without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs according to the basic tariffs. You have a general right of objection without giving reasons (Article 21 (2) GDPR). To do this, click on the unsubscribe link in the respective e-mail or send us your objection to the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

### Newsletter

You have the option of subscribing to our e-mail newsletter on the website or as part of your registration for one of our events, with which we will regularly inform you about the following content:

* new functions of the consent management platform, such as languages, designs, providers and the implementation of new requirements,
* new offers for services of our products and services,
* Invitations to company events.

In order to receive the newsletter, you must provide your name or pseudonym and a valid email address. We process the e-mail address for the purpose of sending our e-mail newsletter and as long as you have subscribed to the newsletter. The legal basis for processing is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 p. 1 lit. a) GDPR.

**You can revoke your consent to the processing of your e-mail address for receiving the newsletter at any time, either by directly clicking on the unsubscribe link in the newsletter or by sending us a message using the contact details given under “Responsible”. This does not affect the lawfulness of the processing that has taken place on the basis of the consent up to the time of your revocation.**

In order to document your subscription to the newsletter and to prevent the misuse of your personal data, registration for our e-mail newsletter takes place in the form of the so-called **double opt-in procedure** . After entering the data marked as mandatory, we will send you an email to the email address you provided, in which we ask you to expressly confirm your subscription to the newsletter by clicking on a confirmation link. We process your IP address, date and time of registration for the newsletter and the time of your confirmation. This way we make sure that you really want to receive our email newsletter. We are legally obliged to prove your consent to the processing of your personal data in connection with the registration for the newsletter (Art. 7 Para. 1 DSGVO). Due to this legal obligation, data processing takes place on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. c) GDPR. You are not obliged to provide your personal data during the registration process. However, if you do not provide the required personal data, we may not be able to process your subscription or not fully process it. If the newsletter subscription is not confirmed within 24 hours, we will block the information transmitted to us. After your confirmation, your data will be processed for as long as you have subscribed to the newsletter.

If you unsubscribe by exercising the revocation of the declaration of consent, we process your data, in particular your e-mail address, to ensure that you will not receive any further newsletters from us. For this purpose, we add your e-mail address to a so-called “ **block list** ”, which means that you will not receive any further newsletters from us. The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. c) GDPR in order to meet our obligations to provide evidence, otherwise Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. In this case, our legitimate interests consist in complying with our legal obligations to reliably no longer send you any newsletters.

**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

In addition, we process the aforementioned data for the establishment **, exercise or defense of legal claims.** The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c) GDPR and Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f) GDPR. In these cases, we have a legitimate interest in asserting or defending against claims.

**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

Registration for events
-----------------------

If you would like to register for an event organized by our company, you must provide the following data:

* First and Last Name,
* Company,
* email address and
* phone number.

We process your data to register for the event and its implementation. The legal basis for processing your data for participation in events is Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit b) GDPR. Your information is required and binding for the conclusion of the contract. If the data is not provided, it is not possible to conclude or implement a contract in the form of registration or participation in the event. We delete your data after storage is no longer necessary, or restrict processing if there are statutory retention requirements.

In this context, your data will be sent to Zoom (Zoom Video Communications Inc., 55 Almaden Blvd. Suite 600, San Jose, CA 95113, USA, hereinafter: “Zoom”) for the purpose of registering for the event, sending event invitations and carrying it out submitted to the event. If you participate in a consentmanager webinar, “Zoom” also processes your access data, such as your IP address, and your image and audio recordings. The legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests lie in the technical provision of our events. “Zoom” also processes your data in the USA. There is no adequacy decision by the EU Commission for the USA. We have concluded so-called standard data protection clauses with “Zoom” in order to oblige “Zoom” to an appropriate level of data protection.

S**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

As part of your registration for one of our events, which we hold together with a partner company, you have the option of registering for our newsletter and the newsletter of the respective partner company. The partner companies are indicated in the relevant form prior to registration. In these cases, we transmit your personal names (such as first and last name and e-mail address) for the purpose of sending the newsletter to the partner company, which is described in more detail in the consent. The legal basis is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. a) GDPR. Further information on data processing in connection with sending our newsletter can be found in the “Email Marketing” section. Information on data processing by the respective partner company can be found in the data protection information of our partner.

You can withdraw your consent to the processing of your e-mail address for receiving the newsletter **You can revoke this at any time, either by clicking directly on the unsubscribe link in the newsletter or by sending us a message using the contact details given under “Responsible”. This does not affect the lawfulness of the processing that has taken place on the basis of the consent up to the time of your revocation.**

Payment Service Provider (PSP)/ payment service provider
--------------------------------------------------------

### PayPal

On our website we offer you payment via “PayPal”. The provider of this payment service is PayPal (Europe) S.à.rl et Cie, SCA, 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg (hereinafter: “PayPal”). To pay, you must log into your PayPal account. The payment details you provide to PayPal will be processed by PayPal for the purpose of payment processing. Further information on data processing by PayPal is available here: [https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full](https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) .

In order to be able to allocate your payment, we process your delivery/billing address, e-mail address and the selected payment method. We delete the data arising in this context after the storage is no longer necessary, or restrict the processing if there are statutory storage obligations. Due to mandatory commercial and tax regulations, we are obliged to keep your address, payment and order data for a period of up to ten years. Two years after the end of the contract, we restrict the processing and reduce the processing to compliance with the existing legal obligations.

The legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR. The provision of your payment data is necessary and obligatory for the conclusion and implementation of the contract. If the payment data is not provided, it is not possible to conclude and/or execute a contract with the “PayPal” payment method.

### Purchase on invoice

In the case of “purchase on account”, we reserve the right to forward the data you provide when ordering to external companies (e.g. Verband der Vereine Creditreform eV, Hellersbergstraße 12, D-41460 Neuss) for the purpose of carrying out a credit check. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests lie in the prevention of fraud and the avoidance of default risks, because we pay in advance for “purchase on account”.

We process the data transmitted to us by your bank as part of the “purchase on account” payment process for the purpose of invoice verification. The legal basis for this processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR. The provision of your payment data is necessary and obligatory for the conclusion and implementation of the contract. If the payment data is not provided, it is not possible to conclude and/or execute a contract by means of a “purchase on account”. We delete the data arising in this context after the storage is no longer necessary, or restrict the processing if there are statutory storage obligations. Due to mandatory commercial and tax regulations, we are obliged to keep your address, payment and order data for a period of up to ten years. Two years after the end of the contract, we restrict the processing and reduce the processing to compliance with the existing legal obligations.

**You can object to the processing if the processing is based on Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

### stripes

The credit card payment options are integrated via “Stripe” (provider is Stripe Inc., Townsend Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA, hereinafter: “Stripe”). If you select one of the payment options mentioned, the payment details you provided during the booking process together with the information about your booking will be passed on to “Stripe” for the purpose of payment processing. The processing takes place on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR. The provision of the payment data is necessary and obligatory for the conclusion and implementation of the contract. If the payment data is not provided, it is impossible to conclude and/or execute a contract with a credit card. As part of the data processing, your data will also be transmitted to the USA. There is no adequacy decision for the USA. However, so-called standard contractual clauses were concluded with “Stripe” in order to oblige “Stripe” to provide an appropriate level of protection. Further information on data protection and the storage period at Stripe can be found at: [https://stripe.com/de/privacy](https://stripe.com/de/privacy) .

### credit card payment

For the purpose of payment processing, we pass on the payment data required for the credit card payment to the bank commissioned with the payment or to the payment and billing service provider commissioned by us. The processing takes place on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. b) GDPR. The provision of your payment data is necessary and obligatory for the conclusion and implementation of the contract. If the payment data is not provided, it is impossible to conclude and/or carry out a contract using a credit card payment. The data required for payment processing are transmitted securely via the “SSL” procedure and processed exclusively for payment processing. We delete the data arising in this context after the storage is no longer necessary, or restrict the processing if there are statutory storage obligations. Due to mandatory commercial and tax regulations, we are obliged to keep your address, payment and order data for a period of up to ten years. Two years after the end of the contract, we restrict the processing and reduce the processing to compliance with the existing legal obligations.

### Legal enforcement / address determination / debt collection

In the event of non-payment, we reserve the right to pass on the data provided during the order to a lawyer and/or to external companies for the purpose of address determination and/or legal enforcement. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. Our legitimate interests lie in the prevention of fraud and the avoidance of default risks. In addition, we may pass on your data in order to ensure that our rights and the rights of our affiliated companies, our cooperation partners, our employees and/or the users of our website are exercised and processing is necessary in this respect. Under no circumstances will we sell or rent your data to third parties. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in processing for law enforcement purposes. We delete the resulting data after the storage is no longer necessary, or restrict the processing if there are statutory storage requirements.

**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

hosting
-------

We use external hosting services from the provider PlusServer GmbH (Hohenzollernring 72, 50672 Cologne, Germany), which serve to provide the following services: infrastructure and platform services, computing capacity, security and technical maintenance services. For these purposes, all data – including the access data mentioned under “Use of our website” – are processed that are required for the operation and use of our website. The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. f) GDPR. With the use of external hosting services, we pursue an efficient and secure provision of our website.

**You can object to the processing. You have the right to object for reasons that arise from your particular situation. You can send us your objection using the contact details given in the “Responsible” section.**

Integration of third-party content
----------------------------------

Content from third parties, such as videos or graphics from other websites, is integrated into the website. This integration always presupposes that the providers of this content (“third-party providers”) perceive the IP addresses of the users. Because without the IP address, they cannot send the content to the browser of the respective user. The IP address is therefore required for the display of this content. We will inform you below about the services of external providers currently used on our website and about the respective processing in individual cases and about your existing objection or revocation options.

### Calendar

To select and arrange a personal appointment or a demo of our consent management platform, we use the online calendar of Calendly, LLC, 3423 Piedmont Road NE, Atlanta, GA 30305-1754, United States (hereinafter: “Calendly”), which has a widget is integrated. When you visit the website, the widget transmits the data specified in the “Use of our website” section to “Calendly”, even if you do not make an appointment. In order to arrange an appointment via the widget, it is necessary to choose the duration of the appointment, a date and a time slot as well as your name, email address, telephone number or Skype name and the topic. This data is also processed by Calendly. After booking the appointment, you will receive an automatically generated email with the data you entered. By processing the data through the widget, we aim to make it easier to book an appointment with us. “Calendly” processes your data for the purposes of advertising, market research and/or needs-based design of its offer. The legal basis for the processing of your data in connection with the use of Calendly is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 p. 1 lit. a) GDPR. If you do not want to make an appointment with us via “Calendly”, please contact us using the contact form on our website. Further information on data processing by our company when contacting us can be found under the “Contacting our company” section. “Calendly” also processes some of the data in the USA. There is no adequacy decision by the EU Commission for data transfer to the USA. The legal basis for the transmission to the USA is your consent in accordance with Art. 49 para. 1 p. 1 lit. a) GDPR. Further information on the purpose and scope of processing by “Calendly” and the storage period at “Calendly” can be found in the data protection declaration at [https://calendly.com/de/privacy](https://calendly.com/de/privacy) .

**You can revoke your consent to data processing and third-country transfers at any time by calling up the consent tool via the icon at the bottom left of the website and unchecking the checkbox under “Advanced Settings”. The lawfulness of the processing remains unaffected until the revocation is exercised.**

### Google Translate

This website uses “Google Translate” from Google (Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001 and Google, LLC 1600 Amphitheater Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA, hereinafter: “Google”) to translate individual words, sentences and the website into other languages. For this purpose, “Google” uses so-called “cookies” (see the “Tracking” section) and establishes a connection to the “Google” servers. With the help of the cookies, “Google” processes the data mentioned under the section “Use of our website” – in particular your IP address and that you have accessed our website – in order to show you a translation of our website. If you are registered as a user with “Google”, Google can assign your visit to our website to your user account and, if necessary, create user profiles across applications. If necessary, “Google” processes your data for the purposes of advertising, market research and/or the needs-based design of its website. The legal basis for processing is your consent in accordance with Article 6 Paragraph 1 Sentence 1 Letter a) GDPR. “Google” also processes some of the data in the USA. There is no adequacy decision by the EU Commission for data transfer to the USA; The legal basis for the transmission to the USA is your consent in accordance with Article 49 (1) sentence 1 lit. a) GDPR. Your data related to “Google Translate” will be deleted after twenty-four months. _Further information on data protection and the storage period can be found at_ [http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy) .

**You can revoke your consent to data processing and third-country transfers at any time by calling up the consent tool via the icon at the bottom left of the website and unchecking the checkbox under “Advanced Settings”. The lawfulness of the processing remains unaffected until the revocation is exercised.**

### YouTube videos

On the website we use plug-ins from the video platform “YouTube.de” or “YouTube.com”, a service provided by YouTube LLC (headquarters at 901 Cherry Avenue, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA; hereinafter “YouTube”), for which “Google” (Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001) is responsible in terms of data protection law. By processing data through the plug-ins, we pursue the purpose of including visual content (“videos”) that we have published on “Youtube.de” or “Youtube.com” on this website as well. The videos are all integrated in “extended data protection mode”, ie no data about you as a user is transmitted to “YouTube” if you do not play the videos. While playing videos on our website, “YouTube” receives the information that you have accessed the corresponding subpage of our website. In addition, some of the data mentioned in the “Use of our website” section is transmitted to “Google”. This occurs regardless of whether “YouTube” provides a user account through which you are logged in, or whether there is no user account. If you are logged in to “Google”, your data will be assigned directly to your account. If you do not wish to be associated with your profile on “YouTube”, you must log out before activating the button. “YouTube” stores your data as usage profiles and processes them independently of the existence of a user account with “Google” for the purposes of advertising, market research and/or the needs-based design of its website. The legal basis for processing is your consent in accordance with Article 6 Paragraph 1 Sentence 1 Letter a) GDPR. “Google” also processes some of the data in the USA. There is no adequacy decision by the EU Commission for data transfer to the USA. The legal basis for the transmission to the USA is your consent in accordance with Article 49 (1) sentence 1 lit. a) GDPR. Further information on the purpose and scope of processing by “YouTube” and the storage period at “YouTube” can be found in the data protection declaration at [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) .

**You can revoke your consent to data processing and third-country transfers at any time by calling up the consent tool via the icon at the bottom left of the website and unchecking the checkbox under “Advanced settings”. The lawfulness of the processing remains unaffected until the revocation is exercised.**

Statistical, analytical and marketing services
----------------------------------------------

We use third-party services for statistical, analysis and marketing purposes. In this way, we are able to provide you with a user-friendly, optimized use of the website. The third parties use cookies, pixels, browser fingerprinting or other tracking technologies to control their services. We will inform you below about the services of external providers currently used on our website as well as about the respective processing in individual cases and about your existing cancellation options.

### etracker

We use the web analysis service “eTracker” (eTracker GmbH, Erste Brunnenstraße 1, 20459 Hamburg, Germany) for the statistical evaluation of visitor access, page views, downloads, previously visited websites and to measure the success of entries in search engines. The “eTracker” tool uses technologies such as “tracking pixels” and “fingerprinting” to collect, analyze and categorize incoming information generated by the user’s device about the use of our website and interactions with our website as well as access data, in particular IP address, browser information previously visited website and date and time of the server request, for the purpose of statistical analysis and range measurement of advertisements in search engines. We use “eTracker” with the extension in which the IP addresses are further processed in abbreviated form in order to make it more difficult to relate them directly to individuals. The legal basis is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 p. 1 lit. a) GDPR. Further information on data protection and the storage period at “eTracker” can be found at: https://www.etracker.com/datenschutz/.

**You can revoke your consent to data processing at any time by calling up the consent tool via the icon at the bottom left of the website and unchecking the checkbox under “Advanced settings”. The lawfulness of the processing remains unaffected until the revocation is exercised.**

Third Party List
----------------

The following third-party providers are used on this website:

cookies
-------

In particular, the following cookies are used on this website:

Navigation

About CMP

consentmanager is a CMP (Consent Management Provider) registered with the IAB with CMP ID 31 on the domain consentmanager.mgr.consensu.org. We provide services to obtain consent from your website visitors and provide this information to your advertisers and other partners.

The consentmanager.de CMP comes with support for over 30 languages, individual designs, reporting, integrated A/B testing & design optimizer as well as an integrated cookie crawler. As one of the few CMP companies that actually come from Europe, we only focus on one thing: making your website GDPR compliant. We do not use “cloud servers” but only our own servers in data centers in Europe. Our customers include news sites, advertising agencies, networks and many others.

Stay in touch …

Qualitäts-Software

See also …

© 2024 consentmanager
